Dipali Makadia

Los Angeles, CA | +1 (562) 825-8686 | dipali.makadia@gmail.com | https://dipalimakadia.github.io/Dipali-s-Portfolio/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dipali-makadia/

SUMMARY

4 years of experience in software development covering frontend, backend, and full-stack tasks, skilled in responsive web
development, W3C standards, cross-browser compatibility, web accessibility, Agile and Scrum methodologies, problem-solving,
troubleshooting, testing, debugging, version control, and client communication.

EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence Intern

Radical Al

06/2024 - present

- Contribute to team efforts in creating 'Kai: The AI Teaching Assistant,' employing Python and TensorFlow for LLMs and RAG models and integrating OpenAI's API to advance natural language capabilities.
- Streamline data processing with PySpark, manage storage with MongoDB, and deploy Redis for caching, bolstering system
 responsiveness and supporting multimodal functionalities.
- Apply multimodal AI techniques, leveraging RNNs and CNNs to refine adaptive learning features, improving learner outcome
 predictions by over 20%.

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant

05/2021 - 01/2022

Collaborated on the O2 project, utilizing HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JIRA, NodeJS, ES6, JavaScript, JQuery, GIT, and Adobe Target to
develop engaging and responsive front-end components.

Associate Interface Developer

Digitas

05/2019 - 05/2021

- Programmed the DMI project with team, using HTML5, CSS3, Highcharts, D3, GIT, Handlebars, NPM, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, and ReactJS to develop visually appealing, interactive graphs and front-end components.
- Built a single-page app containing a dashboard, graphs, roadmap, and calendars, conducted testing.
- Expanded Formula1 project by implementing tracking code and set up data filters using Google Analytics and Jquery. Explored
 new concepts through research using Google Cloud and NodeJS.

Software Developer

Motes & Bots Technologies

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Lead the team on the Smart Office Project to develop a secure and user-friendly website for office management, utilizing ReactJS, Firebase, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, and AWS.
- Features like user authentication and authorization were established, CRUD operations for employee data, and created modules foroffice management.
- Participated in the **Smart Home** application to create a safe and easy-to-use dashboard for home management, using the latest technologies like Angular, Firebase, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, and AWS.
- Gained knowledge of new technologies and implemented software development lifecycle, including the analysis, coding, building, testing, and deployment.

Software Engineer Intern

Textron

07/2017 - 06/2018

Contributed on the Request Tracker website using C#, .NET Framework, HTML, CSS, and SQL Server.
 Collaborated with the team to design a dashboard for tracking requests, performing CRUD operations, creating a user-friendly interface, conducting testing, and fixing bugs.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

01/2022 - 12/2023

California State University Los Angeles GPA - 3.84/4

Master of Technology, Computer Science & Information Security Manipal Institute of Technology 08/2016 - 07/2018

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology

06/2012 - 07/2016

Gujarat Technological University

RECENT PROJECTS

Data Visualization and Management Application (React, React Hooks, JSON, Highcharts, Material UI, Material React Table, export-to-csv, AOS, Firebase)

 Integrated large and complex data into graphs and tables with features including filtering, sorting, downloading CSV files, pagination, and smooth animations.

Automated Restaurant Question-Answering app using ChatGPT API (React, Python, FastAPI, Langchain, OpenAI API, AWS, GIT, Github)

• Defined a query-based restaurant information retrieval app and established a backend system interfacing with the OpenAI API to extract details from restaurant menus. Improved the app's ability to understand and respond to user queries effectively.

Personal Portfolio Website (ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, GIT)

 Designed and developed a personal website showing information that includes education, work experience, projects, skills, and contact details.

Task Management (VueJS, JSON, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, HTML, CSS, Postman API)

• The dynamic and user-friendly task management application includes components such as users, employees, and projects, all uniquely linked and supporting CRUD operations.

Security Algorithms (Java, C/C++)

· Generated security algorithms, such as RSA and DES.

SKILLS

- Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, React Hooks, Redux, Angular, Vue, ES6, Highchart, D3.js
- Backend: Nodejs, Java, Python
- Database: MongoDB, Firebase, SQL Server
- Cloud: AWS, Adobe Targets, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Office, Google Collab, Eclipse, Postman, Wordpress, Photoshop, JIRA, GitHub
- Al Tools: vertexai, streamlit, LLM, Gemini, FastAPI, Generative Al Tools, Large Language Models (LLM), Langchain, FastAPI, OpenAl API
- Additional Skills: API, AJAX, JSON, AEM, Accessibility, Web Services, Software Development Life Cycle, Object-Oriented Programming, GIT, NPM, Gulp/Grunt, Bower, Handlebars, Nodemailer, Linux, Windows, Mac